<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Experience politics from a different angle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/02/01/experience-politics-from-a-different-angle/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/02/01/experience-politics-from-a-different-angle/</id>
    <published>2016-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-03T14:32:56+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="content__p content__intro"&gt;Hansard Society scholars are &lt;strong&gt;aspiring global leaders&lt;/strong&gt; who engage with policy issues at local, national and international levels and build lasting networks abroad. Alumni of this selective and rigorous programme go on to pursue highly successful careers in politics and public service, the law, civil society, academia and commerce. They have included state governors, attorney generals, diplomats, heads of faculty at world-leading universities and business leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;The programme takes a holistic and highly interactive approach to the study of parliamentary democracy and modern British politics. In addition to &lt;a href="/academics/#internship" class="link"&gt;working in Westminster&lt;/a&gt;, scholars examine nationalism and devolution first hand during the &lt;a href="/academics/#study-trips" class="link"&gt;integral study visits&lt;/a&gt; to the Scottish Parliament in Edinburgh and the National Assembly for Wales in Cardiff, providing a truly comparative experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="testimonial-lg testimonial-lg--text"&gt;
  &lt;p class="testimonial-lg__quote"&gt;Learn about topical issues from senior politicians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;Regular guest lectures, as well as invitations to high profile events at Westminster, enable scholars to learn about the topical issues of the day from senior politicians, media commentators, prominent academics and experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;Our bespoke &lt;a href="/academics" class="link"&gt;political science courses&lt;/a&gt; are taught by academics from leading British institutions and are offered in association with the London School of Economics and Political Science.  Scholars have full access to the LSE’s world-renowned social science collection.*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;Administered by the UK’s leading parliamentary think tank, Hansard Society Scholars is unique among study abroad political internship programmes. Through the Society’s exceptional links with the Palace of Westminster and the devolved legislatures, the programme provides an unrivalled opportunity to undertake pre-professional work experience with key figures in British politics. Taken alongside academic courses that underpin the programme, the placement challenges scholars to understand and apply theoretical concepts and research within a working environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;All of this and more takes place in one of the world’s greatest capital cities, steeped in history and tradition and rich in culture, yet modern and vibrant.  There is something for everyone in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;We hope you will enjoy reading about the experiences of some of our recent scholar alums in our new &lt;a href="/blog" class="link"&gt;‘Westminster Calling’ blog&lt;/a&gt;, starting with the &lt;a href="/2016/02/01/a-welsh-love-story/" class="link"&gt;discovery of a whole nation by Melanie Zook!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;Our application process has been redesigned to make the experience as simple as possible. All application materials can be submitted online, but the option to mail us your documents is still available.  Please feel free to contact us if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="footnote"&gt;* This Programme should not be confused with the LSE’s own Parliamentary Internship scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Welsh Love Story</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/02/01/a-welsh-love-story/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/02/01/a-welsh-love-story/</id>
    <published>2016-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-01T01:55:07+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="content__p content__intro"&gt;When I tell people back home in Texas that I worked in the UK Parliament for Plaid Cymru, the Party of Wales, they respond with blank faces. &lt;strong&gt;“Wales? Is that in England?”&lt;/strong&gt; they say, allowing me to launch into an absurdly impassioned speech about the glories of this small, poetic nation that has fought to maintain its language and identity for hundreds of years in the face of English tyranny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;A year ago, though, I would have been as confused as everyone else. When I received my internship placement from the Hansard Society Scholars programme, the first thing I did was Google “Wales.” Is it a country? A region? And what exactly is “Plad Kimroo” anyway? When I realized on my first day of work that everyone in my office spoke Welsh fluently and often, my stomach dropped even more – I was in way over my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="testimonial-lg testimonial-lg--text"&gt;
  &lt;p class="testimonial-lg__quote"&gt;I fell in love with Wales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;But here’s the thing: there is no point studying abroad if you’re not ready to embrace the unknown. So I embraced Wales wholeheartedly, doing as much research as I could, asking my co-workers plenty of questions, and taking every opportunity I could to visit different parts of the nation. And that’s how I fell in love with Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;Through the Hansard study visit to Cardiff, I saw Wales’s oppressed history in Cardiff Castle and its bright future in the Senedd. After the Plaid conference in Caernarfon, I ate Welsh rarebit stew and learned about &lt;em&gt;hiraeth&lt;/em&gt;, a yearning for a long-lost home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;While campaigning in Ceredigion, I met not only my first sheep, but also my first American-turned-Welshman who had grown similarly attached to Wales on her own study abroad program. And in London, I watched my first Welsh rugby match while drinking a pint of Brains and screaming “Come on, Wales!” with a crowd of homesick Welshmen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="testimonial-lg testimonial-lg--text"&gt;
  &lt;p class="testimonial-lg__quote"&gt;One of the most awe-inspiring places in the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;Through the Hansard programme, I had the opportunity to not only intern in Parliament, one of the most awe-inspiring places in the world, but also to engage in a nation and culture I would otherwise likely never have discovered. The impact is lasting, too; after completing my senior year at Rice University, I plan to return to the UK for graduate work on the Welsh education system, a subject I became interested in after talking to my co-workers about their own schooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;I needed to get thrown into the deep end on my study abroad, to get jolted out of my comfort zone and forced to choose between complacency and adventure. I chose the latter, threw myself into the experience, and never looked back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="content__p"&gt;So &lt;em&gt;diolch&lt;/em&gt;, Hansard, for introducing me to Wales. I think we will be very happy together.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
